Did you not hear me?
I said to let me pass.
I have no business
with you, Assassin.
And did you not hear me when I
said to force your way through?
If you do not hurry, your
Master's life will be forfeit.
Don't be so angry
at Assassin, Caster.
He faces Saber.
I don't know who
that samurai is,
but he must be a master swordsman
indeed to hold Saber at bay.
Shouldn't you be
complimenting him instead?
Surely you jest.
I could hardly consider him a hero
if he failed to stop the likes of you.
That man lacks the skill to call
himself a master swordsman.
Saber is here?
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
The Reward for the Death Match
How can this be?
Heft, power, speed...
I have the advantage
in every field.
Why can't I break his defense?
Oh, well done.
I should have taken your head seven
times, and yet it remains attached.
It appears Western swordplay
is more than mere flailing after all.
I commend you as well.
For a man of such slight build,
your technique is impressive.
If nothing else, you
are skilled in trickery.
Of course. You have the
edge in both strength and spirit.
That leaves me only
my wiles to defeat you.
I have also nearly adjusted
to your invisible sword.
From that brief
exchange of blows?
Does this Servant surpass me
so greatly in sword technique?
Now, let us continue.
Show me what you are
really capable of, Saber.
Shirou...
Hold on.
From what you've said,
your Masters work together?
Work together?
Yes...
Assassin guards the gate,
and Caster lurks within.
Isn't it obvious that the
two of them are allies?
It isn't particularly unusual.
For example, you and
Rin have also joined forces.
Me? Work with that dog?
With Assassin, who is
no more than my pawn?
Your pawn?
Yes.
That dog has no Master
of his own, so to speak.
What?
Caster!
You broke the rules!
What is wrong with a mage such
as myself summoning a Servant?
Caster summoned Assassin?
You're saying that a Servant
summoned another Servant?
That gatekeeper there, not summoned by
a proper Master, is not the true Assassin.
She broke the rules and summoned
an Assassin-class Servant herself.
Establishing this as her territory, she
harvests souls from people in the city.
She herself doesn't fight
but rather monitors the
battle through eyes she
placed throughout town.
The three knight classes, including
Saber, are less susceptible to magic.
It's only natural for a
magic-user class such
as yourself to resort
to underhanded tactics.
But you chose to do this on
your own, didn't you, Caster?
What makes you say that?
Masters are mages too.
Anyone who summoned a mage
more powerful than themselves
would be on guard, even
with Command Spells.
Given that, it's hard to believe a Master
would let you summon a Servant to obey you.
In which case,
I can imagine you've
long since made a puppet
of him, like this fool
of a Master behind me.
Winning the Holy Grail War
would be a simple matter.
My considerable efforts are
directed toward what comes after.
Oh?
You say it would be
simple to defeat us?
You, a witch who does
nothing but slink in the shadows?
Yes. In this place, you may
not so much as scratch me.
I shall mete out an appropriate punishment
upon those who would call me a witch.
Not even a scratch, you claim?
One blow, then.
If that is not enough, I
shall leave the rest to Saber.
Too bad, Archer.
Spatial transportation?
Innate time control?
Within this territory, you
can imitate true magic?
You impress me, Caster.
And you disappoint me, Archer.
I sought to test you, thinking you might
be useful, but you are worse than Assassin.
I'm sorry to hear it.
If I get another chance, I'll try
harder to live up to your expectations.
You vixen.
You have a huge store of
mana to draw on, don't you?
Do you think you can escape?
That imbecile!
Oh, crap.
Put me down, you idiot!
What are you thinking?
The hell if I know!
And hearing you of all people say that
makes me feel really stupid, you idiot!
Idiot?
If you know you're
being stupid, then what
right do you have to
call other people idiots?
Idiot!
What are you, a child?
If you're both an idiot and
a child, you're a lost cause.
Pick one and stick
with it, numbskull!
What did you say to me?
Put me down, damn it!
I can handle this myself!
Can you, now?
You son of a...
How does that feel, Archer?
Even the three knight classes cannot
move if space itself is immobilized.
This would appear
to be checkmate.
I don't know which hero
you were, but this is farewell.
What was that, Archer?
If you wish to beg
for your life, I can...
Imbecile!
I said, "Dodge this," Caster!
That's...
I am the bone of my sword.
Caladbolg!
It seems that matters do not
progress as planned up there.
My Master is in peril, so I no longer have
the luxury of concealing my true skill.
Even now, you will not
reveal your Noble Phantasm.
Your Master is a beginner, so you
count on the strength of his luck?
Your trust in him is admirable.
I see that halfhearted
measures cannot break it.
However, that
simply will not do.
You yield the advantage
of higher ground?
What are you playing at?
I may be a no-name Servant, but I
have devoted my life to the sword.
If I cannot convince you
to give your all for this fight,
shall I break open that
belief with brute force?
Secret technique:
Swallow Reversal!
Too late!
Archer, why do you
not finish me off?
I said I would test you
with a single blow, did I not?
You don't intend
to kill me, then?
My objective was this boy.
My policy is to avoid
unnecessary fighting.
Hey...
I see.
You two are quite alike, then.
That boy cannot abide a Servant
like me who feeds on the innocent.
And you dislike
senseless slaughter.
See? You're
practically identical.
How am I anything
like this jerk?
Agreed.
I admit we may both be pacifists,
but that is for entirely different reasons.
You call yourself a pacifist?
You think I'd forget that you tried to
destroy Saber along with Berserker?
That was before we
struck an alliance.
Surely you don't expect me to
try and save everything in sight.
If you follow that
reasoning, even Berserker
would be something
to save, not defeat.
I like you two!
Your powers and
personalities are unique.
Join forces with me.
I have the means to
put an end to this war.
Never!
I refuse to work
with people like you.
Damn it, Archer! Hey!
I'll pass.
Your team has limited
fighting potential.
No matter how much power you
gain, you are no match for Berserker.
What you offer isn't enough
for me to ally myself with you.
I see. Looks like we have ourselves
a breakdown in negotiations.
We do.
Besides, I've come
here of my own volition.
My Master did not send me,
so I have no reason to kill you.
Shall we call this a
draw due to injury?
Hey, now...
I'm surprised.
Your Master has been
hunting me, has she not?
And yet you would let me go?
Yes.
It is no concern of mine
how many you kill here.
My goodness.
What a callous man you are.
Wait a minute, Caster!
Archer, why did
you let Caster go?
Even if I'd struck her down, she
would have simply made her escape.
To defeat Caster, we
must get to her Master.
But all the incidents
in town are her doing.
The victims will keep
piling up until we stop her.
On the contrary, I
want to let her continue.
Caster will keep
draining people of their life
force and will use that
power to defeat Berserker.
Then we'll deal with
Caster afterward.
Tohsaka would never do that!
You're right,
which is why I'd like Caster to
settle matters as soon as possible.
I don't know how many will die,
but humans are mortal, after all.
However they die, and at whose
hands, the end result is the same.
You withstood my
secret technique.
It is not all that
special, as tricks go.
It's simply something I mastered
when I thought to slay a swallow.
A flying swallow will not be caught
by my sword, which is but a single line.
But with two or three lines,
matters change somewhat.
However, swallows
are swift little things.
To succeed, one must strike
repeatedly within a single breath.
A feat beyond the
ability of any normal man.
But unfortunately, I
had nothing better to do.
Mastery through
endless repetition.
The next thing I knew,
I had accomplished it.
That isn't right.
"Strike repeatedly
within a single breath"?
Those blows were simultaneous.
At that instant,
three swords existed.
As difficult as
it is to believe...
That was a dimensional warp.
A Servant who, through
conventional swordsmanship alone,
created a technique on
par with a Noble Phantasm...
Caster is a fool.
She should have taken their
lives while she had the chance.
It would be easier to fight if
everyone in the city was dead already.
You...
I thought we had an alliance.
Don't give me that!
I'm nothing like you.
I would never sacrifice those
around me to achieve victory or a goal!
I feel the same
way, Emiya Shirou.
But it is impossible
to save everyone.
If Caster wins the Grail, the damage
won't be limited to this city alone.
If we should fail, far
more people will die.
Therefore, the only choice is
to sacrifice this city's people.
If that ends up minimizing
the overall losses,
then it's in line
with your ideology.
Saving one person
means not saving another.
You said you didn't want to
involve innocent people, didn't you?
Then admit it.
If you try to avoid killing anyone,
you won't save anyone in the end.
You plan to go after Caster?
Do you mean to waste that
life I took such pains to sa...
Shut up!
I wouldn't want your
help, even if you offered!
I see.
Your dislike of me
makes this easier.
Archer?
You...
Emiya Shirou, if there is no
meaning to your fight, then die here.
Fighting for others but not
yourself is nothing but hypocrisy.
It isn't victory that
you want. It's peace.
Unfortunately for you,
there's no such thing.
What?
Farewell.
Let your ideals drag
you to your death.
Shirou!
That vixen...
She retreated?
Saber...
Assassin, why did you not
strike me down just now?
I was captivated, you see.
You were attractive when we fought, but
your concern for your Master is exquisite.
My admiration stayed my hand.
That is enough for tonight.
You may leave.
You're letting us go?
I am indeed.
To find a worthy
opponent is a rare thing.
It would be a waste to defeat you
at anything short of your peak form.
Or would you consider
this a favor owed, Saber?
Of course, Sasaki Kojirou.
Forgive my rudeness.
You were truly an opponent
worthy of my full attention.
Rest assured, I shall
settle things with you,
regardless of the outcome
of the Holy Grail War.
I swear it.
You stand in my way, samurai?
I should ask you the same.
You would interfere after
I allowed them to leave?
My duty is to guard this gate.
I permitted entry, but
egress is another matter.
Your head lacks elegance, but I shall
satisfy myself by claiming it tonight.
You think you can fight
me, lackey of Caster?
I could say the same.
I sent you to give
the vixen a scare,
so imagine my disappointment
to see you flee for your life.
Shirou, let us withdraw.
Hurry!
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
I understand.
So Archer allowed
Caster to escape?
Yeah, he did.
That guy is the worst.
If he's willing to exploit
someone like Caster to win,
he's no better than her.
What's so funny?
Well, it is rare to hear
you speak ill of someone.
But you aren't angry at
Archer for attacking you?
I'm allied with
Tohsaka. Not him.
If you look at it that
way, he didn't betray me.
You are truly
fascinating, Shirou.
Indeed, Caster cannot
be allowed to run free,
but I believe Archer is
not as cruel as you think.
Hang on a second.
Were you listening
to a single thing I said?
You saw it, didn't you, Shirou?
His technique was as
pure as a clear stream.
His heart must
be equally as pure.
He's not that
great with a sword.
He got the drop on me from behind,
but he still didn't manage to kill me.
Yes, you have talent as well.
With enough time and effort, you
should be able to reach his level.
I've made up my mind.
Once I've recovered, teach
me how to use a sword.
Not just for exercise.
Teach me how to fight.
Very well.
If that's what you want, Shirou.
That settles it, then!
I can't screw up
again like I did tonight,
and running away at every
turn won't change anything.
Most of all, I can't let
myself lose to that bastard
who said he'd sacrifice
the few to save the many.
Ow!
We're going to bring
down that magic field.
The enemy is planning
to settle things here.
I'll make you pay for what
you've done, no matter what!
That's great!
This is how
Servants ought to be!
Winter Days, Where the Heart Is
Next Time